{
  "reference_number": "10892",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a goal to reach net zero emissions by the second half of the century and the Climate Change Commission advises on the specific target for the Government to set later",
      "answer_index": 11,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Long-Lived Gases and Stabilised Short-Lived Gases - Long-lived gases to net zero by 2050 while also stabilising short-lived gases",
      "answer_index": 12,
      "notes": "Methane emissions are at net zero when the level of emissions are stable (which it is now). This carbon dioxide equivalent system is\n flawed. Over one third of these carbon emissions are fictional because methane is so over-stated. Most, if any, of these methane\n\n emissions don't alter composition of atmosphere."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Do these budgets cover CO2 sequestered by trees, soil etc on agricultural land against NTO and any net increase in atmospheric\n methane? e.g. net emissions for farmers, also land covered with concrete and asphalt in city areas"
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "None of the above. Any budget should be able to be altered as technical/scientific/economic/social/energy etc events happen and\n change."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "None of the above. As per question 6"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "As per question 6 in regard to budgets"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Food and security v global warming. Costs incurred on everyone e.g. power. Emissions moving overseas e.g. businesses moving\noverseas. Use of GMO, nuclear energy to replace fossil fuels?"
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Depends what the measurements are based on"
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Neither, methane emitters treated unfairly in ETS e.g. Air NZ could offset carbon with tree planting, pay no ETS - farmers with stable\n\nstock numbers have net zero methane emissions however will still pay ETS"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "More people with crystal balls!!"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Energy - loss of fossil fuels. What's to be used for industry, the powering of electric cars, domestic consumption. What is a low cost\n\nalternative, nuclear? Updating of RMA to allow more dams, solar, wind and nuclear and GMO alternatives. Where does the billions of\nfunds that flow from fossil fuels and agriculture come from after they have been disrupted? Green manufacturing will go to Asia where\nthey have cheap coal power (60 plants built in the last 2 years). Expensive green innovation will go to where the main capital (money)\n\nis. Who gets the billions that countries will be paying (based on flawed science) and what will the people be left with? The non-\nsecurity of food and energy leads to civil unrest."
    }
  ]
}
